The topic of this project is the classification of drug consumers using artificial intelligence. 
To begin with, it is necessary to look at the database and determine the set of input and output data. 
The output consists of the following substances: alcohol, amphetamine, amyl, benzos, caffeine, cannabis, chocolate, cocaine, crack, ecstasy, heroin, ketamine, legal boosters, methadone, fungi, nicotine, semester (fictitious drug), VSA (abuse of volatile substances). 
Data on the consumption of individual substances are not evenly distributed, and the paper will select the substances that will be most suitable for solving the classification problem. 
After selecting the output variables (alcohol, ecstasy, cannabis and nicotine), two types of classification will be performed:
➢ binary and
➢ multiclass classification.
The thesis will be divided into the above classifications. For each classification, for all selected substances, the following machine learning algorithms will be applied:
➢ Multilayer Perceptron-MLP,
➢ method of support vectors engl. Support vector machine (SVM),
➢ k- nearest neighbors engl. k- nearest neighbors (KNN).
The results will then be observed using a number of different metrics:
➢ confusion matrix,
➢ accuracy, precision, sensitivity,
➢ AUC-ROC.
The confusion matrix will be applied to the binary classification and will help in reviewing the classification results. 
Accuracy, precision, and sensitivity will be important metrics for reviewing results after binary classification, while the AUC-ROC curve will be more important for reviewing results after multiclass classification (although it will also be applied to binary classification).

